<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Natsuko&#39;s Blog</title>
    <description>Natsuko&#39;s Daily Adventures in Nepal</description>
    <link>http://naztshinozaki.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://naztshinozaki.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2016 14:57:17 +0545</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2016 14:57:17 +0545</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Teej - Fasting for the First Time!</title>
        <description>I got to experience my first &lt;strong&gt;Teej&lt;/strong&gt;, the largest women’s festival in Nepal! Teej is a celebration where women gather together to fast for the longevity and health of their husbands, worship at the temples and dance. My Nepali sister Depa first told me about this festival four years ago, and she was super excited when she knew that I would be here during this time. In fact, that was one of the first things she exclaimed about - that I would finally be able to celebrate Teej with her - when I said that I would be staying in Nepal for the whole year. &lt;strong&gt;This was something I could not miss&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;


It all started with my dress picking for the day, about a week ago. Two of my friends brought me out to shop for the perfect garment for the occasion. In the small Sari shop that I was brought to in Mangal Bazar (I honestly don’t know how people find these stores in the nook and crooks of the street), I was thrown a whole array of options. &lt;i&gt;Choosing these garments are an intense matter&lt;/i&gt;. I tried them on, one after another. After much prodding, twirling, and tightening of the loose cloth on my body, we settled on a blue and orange Lehenga. After that we also went to pick out the shoes, accessories, and fixed the Lehenga at the tailor shop -  all with deliberate contemplation. Then finally I was set for the day.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;


Teej this year fell on Sunday. So from Saturday evening, I went over to Depa’s house and enjoyed a feast of all kinds of delicious dishes and sweets. All Depa’s relatives from young to old, we  all pre-danced in our pyjamas. We went pretty wild, thrusting out our moves to the music from the cell phone. We ate again at 11 pm, just before it turned the next day when we had to begin our fast. I was not very hungry but I helped myself to the late night feast of coconut and almond mixed rice, yogurt, and some traditional sweets. I was full to the max but still ate because I was pretty nervous about feeling hungry the next day.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;


&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/teej6.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:600px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

I woke up not hungry, but still I was a bit worried about how I could go through the day without drinking any water or food till sunset. But the purpose of the festival wasn’t endurance, so I tried to brush the thought out of my head and enjoy the day. We got up and began preparing for our visit to the temple, which basically meant putting on lots of make up. I’ve never put on so much makeup, but it felt pretty great having myself- beautified and being told that I look like a Nepali girl (um, girl?!). The temple was a vibrant color of red and green saris with the beautifully embroided Saris. Look at these beauties! &lt;br&gt;


&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/teej5.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:600px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/teej1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:330px; width:450px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/teej2.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:330px; width:450px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/teej3.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:600px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

Ok I’m going to spill the beans but I was not able to do a full fasting that day. After dancing becoming all hot and sweaty, I gave into drinking water. I swear I could have endured it but when some of my friends drank some water, I just couldn’t resist. I abstained from eating food though till sunset. I never imagined that it was be so hard, I felt pretty dizzy and low on energy by 3pm. Again it’s probably because I wasn’t entirely fasting for a purpose, I was fasting more for formality. Depa always used to tell me that the days she fasts she never feels hungry, but instead feels good from the purity of what she is doing and the holiness associated with it. It was an interesting experience to fast, putting myself in the shoes of so many others who fast as part of their religion. The act definitely takes a toll on the body. But the beliefs associated now I see now is &lt;i&gt;so powerful and meaningful&lt;/i&gt; to those who practice it, that it is far more gratifying that satisfying the immediate needs of your body. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;


When I had my first bite of the milky sweets at 5pm, I felt the sugar in it flowing through my blood and nourishing my body. &lt;i&gt;I felt revitalized&lt;/i&gt;. It’s amazing how that little piece could give you so much energy.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;


&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/teej7.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:600px;&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
 
I came back for the night, but I will be returning back again tomorrow for another full day of dancing in the temple. I’m super grateful to Depa and her family for inviting me to be part of their family festivities, and Nepali culture. I loved all the colors and the joy in the air, and i’m definitely looking forward tomorrow for another day of dancing and fun (and this time food!). </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/09/05/Teej.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/09/05/Teej.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Gap Between the Job Market and Higher Education in the IT Field</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After stuffing ourselves, we returned back to the office to host our small discussion session event at TECHRISE. We invited a couple of startup guys, web developers and some college administrators. The purpose of the session was to discuss about the existing gap between the &lt;strong&gt;job market and higher education in the IT field&lt;/strong&gt;. I wanted to bring to one table these people who all worked in this field but in various spaces, to have a frank and open discussion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/discussion1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:590px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through our nearly two-hour conversation we realized that the gap that we were trying to identify was not only limited to simply the gap between what is required by the job market and what is being taught at the educational institutions. There were multiple so-called &lt;i&gt;gaps&lt;/i&gt;, which all came into play to create this disparity and disconnect. Some of these gaps that we identified were:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The gap between the &lt;i&gt;demands from the &lt;strong&gt;industry&lt;/strong&gt; (wants experienced and qualified individuals) and the &lt;strong&gt;students&lt;/strong&gt; (do not have any experience and very little qualifications)&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The gap between the &lt;i&gt;skills students acquire and what is required from the job market&lt;/i&gt; – Many of the concepts and content are outdated and not in demand&lt;/li&gt;


&lt;li&gt;The gap between the &lt;i&gt;talent the students wish to supply and the demand from the market&lt;/i&gt; - There are not enough industries that are monetizable. People cannot make a living unless you are working in a highly in demand sector (not limited to the IT sector)&lt;/li&gt; &lt;br /&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/discussion2.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:590px;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other interesting points that came up were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The lack of motivation among students – perhaps linked to the fact that there are limited opportunities to see how what they learned can be applied to the real world&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The importance of students nurturing a problem solving attitude, instead of a passive learning one&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The culture of &lt;i&gt;blame&lt;/i&gt;: students blaming teachers for not being able to understand and perform, and vice versa teachers blaming students&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were so many factors that were interrelated to constructing this discrepancy. The conversation is a never-ending one with no real conclusion. But from the discussion, I think we came to realize that there are two roles that we can take on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.	To inspire the students to apply their skills to the real world, and motivate them to pursue further with academics at school &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.	Help them become real problem solvers through curriculum design (you can learn more about the TECHRISE learning system though this  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.techrise.me/posts/how-techrise-creates-superstar-coders&quot;&gt;  blog &lt;/a&gt;) and providing more opportunities to work on real live projects &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an educational entity that really cares about doing what’s best for the students and their learning, we found everyone’s insights extremely valuable. Their willingness to sacrifice a Saturday afternoon to hold this conversation really showed their passion towards what they did in this field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a long day for us but a really meaningful weekend!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/08/28/Discussion-Event.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/08/28/Discussion-Event.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>8th NasCOIT Keynote Speech</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Saturday was another hectic day full of events. 
First of all there was the 8th National Student Conference on Information Technology - one of the most prestigious IT related events o the year. I’m not sure how they found us or why they decided to approach us, but about 3 weeks ago, the organizer of this event suddenly contacted us. Their invitation to deliver the keynote speech was all so abrupt with their sudden appearance at our office door, we simply said yes. 
So to be honest we were really not expecting the kind of grandeur that awaited us at the venue. The conference was held at a famous five star hotel in Kathmandu, the Yak and Yeti Hotel. &lt;i&gt;Boy was it grand&lt;/i&gt;. It was a huge, almost palace like building with well-groomed bellboys, guards and everything. The inside was gorgeous and even air-conditioned! When we saw the crowd all suited up, we immediately regretted our attire. Not that we had much of a choice I guess though. Take was wearing slacks and his best polo, while I was wearing the only skirt I had brought. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/NaSCoIT1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:590px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The morning session in which Take delivered the short speech mostly ended with remarks from the organizers / important seniors involved. He talked about the importance of blending in technology (e-learning models) with the human factor that supplements the learning. As a final message, he implored the audience to consider developing the educational field through technology in Nepal as IT professionals. &lt;strong&gt; While there are so many outstanding e-learning type of innovations out there in the world, they cannot be directly imported to Nepal without adapting it to the Nepali context and curriculum. &lt;/strong&gt; I think there is loads of potential especially in Nepal where there are so many different kinds of edcational challenges. But again I suppose that it is necessary to construct an &lt;i&gt;incentive system&lt;/i&gt; where people are rewarded for their efforts in developing the educational sector. Without proper monitary incentives, I think it’s highly unlikely that the brightest minds will divert their time and effort there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/NasCoIT2.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:440px; height:590px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had to hurry back right after lunch so unfortunately we weren’t able to hear a bunch of student presentations, which was the highlight of the event. The lunch was amazing by the way. It was a delicious buffet with different kind of salads, curries and desserts. I think our enthusiasm towards the food was a little too much, as we devoured our first plate in minutes and headed back for seconds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The afternoon discussion event held at TECHRISE will be continued in the next blog post :) Lot of interesting findings on what’s actually happening at the industry level and the educational level.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/08/28/8th-NaSCoIT.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/08/28/8th-NaSCoIT.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Freelancing Event Round 2</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today we held our second public seminar on “How to Start Your Freelancing Career” at TECHRISE. The last time we decided to hold the same seminar, which was two weeks ago, more than 70 people registered to attend. We ended up having to select only 30 due to the limited space in our office. Seeing that it was a great hit, we decided to hold a second round of the same seminar. This time too, we got over a 130 sign ups so we just decided to go for two sessions in one day. I suppose we should have closed the form earlier, but we were just curious to see how many would respond!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason why we came to choose this topic was because both Take and I have had quite a lot of experience freelancing as a part time job. I mostly translate, while Take has recently been taking on more web development projects. We discovered freelancing about two years ago, with a Japanese freelancing platform. &lt;i&gt;It was a total game changer for us.&lt;/i&gt; Initially it was hard getting projects with the competition, but eventually we were able to get more gigs as we experimented with our profile and our approaches to clients. After playing around with different ways to market ourselves, we began to earn quite a nice amount of pocket money. We were even able to earn back our travelling expense for our vacation by working a couple hours a day during that vacation (we still had fun, honestly!). We became workaholics in a way, but we loved the freedom of being able to work from anywhere, and doing as much or as less as we wished to. I honestly wouldn’t have been able to gain the experiences I have had so far, or even come to Nepal if I wasn’t backed up financially with what I earned from freelancing. Some of the tactics that we used in freelancing worked like magic, and once we got hold of it, things came pretty easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So our presentation was mostly around the tips and tricks we accumulated over the couple of years. I hope people found it useful – I mean, I certainly wish someone could have told me some of these things when we first started off! 31 participants turned up in each session, and the room was packed with human bodies. Mostly IT students, as well as some professional designers and web developers came out today. Even some who were currently working were interested because apparently they couldn’t really make it just by working for their company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/freelance2.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:590px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having two sessions in a day was pretty tough, but it was a lot of fun interacting with the participants during and after the presentation. Besides, in between presentations Lakshman and Aadesh ordered Momos so that we would get that oily energy boost ;) 
Some seemed to be genuinely interested in what we do at TECHRISE. I hope we were able to get some TECHRISE fans though this event!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/freelance1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:590px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/08/26/Freelancing-Event-Round-2.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/08/26/Freelancing-Event-Round-2.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Refreshing Morning at Soma Cafe</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I’ve been slightly restless. I’m not sure why but I’m guessing bits of fatigue and from being cooped up in the office too much. I love our building because we wake up, go down to the office to work, go up on the terrace to eat, and go even down to hang out with friends at the restaurant in the evening. But after following the routine of going up and down the flights of stairs daily, I wanted to have a bit of a change and spend a morning nice café. And have some good coffee that I have been missing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So after waking up, instead of going straight up to our kitchen we got changed and grabbed a tempo on the main road. Tempos are small open busses that are super convenient for short rides because you can basically stop anywhere you ask them to if its along the way. The drive up was only about 5 minutes – a much shorter ride than usual because the roads were super empty. Taking public transport was the hassle I usually didn’t enjoy, there were always too many people and the heat could really fry you. The ride today was sweet and short though, with a slight breeze coming in from the back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’m at Café Soma now, a café popular among the expat community. We came here twice before, on two special occasions where we met Karmath from Cloud Factory and Jeremiah who was also developing an online curriculum for coding. On both occasions we had a great time talking for well over two and a half hours, so the place was associated with good conversations and positive energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The atmosphere reminded me somewhat of DC, which I spent a school year in last year as an exchange student. Meetings were being held everywhere, and from each table you could catch snippets of really passionate people discussing some important sounding stuff. A lot like DC, where every coffee shop I went to some policy makers, government officials, large international organization personnel were huddled brewing up some impressive schemes. Sometimes I would pretend I’m doing my homework while really listening in on some game changing plans that were being made next to me. Café Soma had something similar in its atmosphere, buzzing with conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/soma2.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:590px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We ordered coffees and a muffin. Coffee. We’ve been drinking instant coffee, and compared to that the coffee here was on a whole new level. I’m not a coffee fanatic but after picking up the habit of drinking some over-priced coffee in DC last year, I’ve come to enjoy a good cup of brewed coffee. The chocolate chip muffin I ordered wasn’t bad either. Not as great as the calorie packed pastries that I gorged on so much, but one of the best ones I had here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also picked up a book at a near by bookstore called “Fatalism and Development – Nepal’s struggle for modernization”, written by a Nepalese anthropologist. Jeremiah recommended the book and it seems super interesting – right on point where my interest lies. The shopkeeper Bipin also recommended us a couple more about Nepal’s history, social issues and politics. I can’t wait to read all of them but I’m going to go one by one so I can have something to look forward to. The books here in Nepal are super cheap too apparently because they are printed in India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/book.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:300px; height:400px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The morning was a nice refresher from our daily schedule. It was so enjoyable that I think this is going to turn out to be a weekly routine!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/08/25/A-Refreshing-Morning-at-Soma-Cafe.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/08/25/A-Refreshing-Morning-at-Soma-Cafe.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Stand-Up Meetings</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Glancing up at the calendar it surprises me that we are still into our third week since officially launching TECHRISE. I’m not saying that we have been so successful that we can’t believe our achievements over the past third weeks. Rather, we are surprised at how much we have been able to progress based on our un-successes we have had. TECHRISE is not what it was a week ago, neither is it what it was a day before. I think we have been doing a pretty good job evolving daily, adapting and responding to the daily needs of our students and the market. The reason we are able to do this? I would attribute it most to out daily &lt;strong&gt;Stand-Up meetings&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stand-Up meetings are short meetings daily that many start-ups and agile software developments adopt. They are intended to be &lt;i&gt;short&lt;/i&gt; – short enough that people can do it while their standing up, hence the name Stand-up meetings. We use this method too, and what we do is go around the table each simply saying a couple of sentences on&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; 1. What you have been working on&lt;br /&gt;
2. What you are going to work on today &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it. These are the two things we recite during our 5-minute meetings. No fuss and no lengthy discussions on this and that.&lt;br /&gt;
This method is amazing because:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4 id=&quot;it-forces-you-to-move-on-with-tasks-and-keeps-you-accountable&quot;&gt;It forces you to move on with tasks and keeps you accountable&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You certainly don’t want to be saying that you have been working on xx task for three consecutive days - that would be awkward.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4 id=&quot;it-helps-you-understand-who-has-been-working-on-what&quot;&gt;It helps you understand who has been working on what&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It helps us communicate the progress made on the marketing team (Lakshman and Natsuko) and the developer team (Take and Aadesh) especially because we don’t work together so often.  It also opens doors to ways in which we can help each other.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4 id=&quot;it-helps-set-the-mood-for-the-day&quot;&gt;It helps set the mood for the day&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It puts you on the go mode!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other than our daily meetings, another way we keep in check what we have been doing individually as well as a team is by writing &lt;strong&gt;weekly logs&lt;/strong&gt;. Basically each Sunday we write in a Google Spread Sheet &lt;strong&gt;1. What was good about TECHRISE that week, 2. What needs improvements, 3. What kind of personal growth you had.&lt;/strong&gt; This really helps us get a more birds eye view on how TECHRISE is doing, and helps us create actionable goals for the week. The personal growth part I wanted to add in because I wanted everyone to feel his or her personal development through being involved in TECHRISE. I think this would be useful when the organization is in dooms day, because we can always look back and say &lt;i&gt;“Hey, at least we learned something”&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Growing up in Japan, I’ve often found my self in long dreary meetings where frankly I didn’t find was really going anywhere. The &lt;strong&gt;5-minute Stand-Up meetings &lt;/strong&gt;as well as our &lt;strong&gt;weekly logs&lt;/strong&gt; have been doing wonders for me though! I highly recommend this to any startup or organization if they aren’t already using this method. It’s life changing :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/08/24/Stand-Up-Meetings.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/08/24/Stand-Up-Meetings.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Festival at Nirman&#39;s Village</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday we went to a festival at our good friend Nirman and Saru’s village. They had been talking about this festival since the time we arrived here a month ago, so there was no way we were not going. 
Upon arriving at the village center, we could immediately tell that something special was about to happen. People filled every nook and corner of the square, and faces poked out of every window. This was a village festival held annually, a tradition of around 600 years where the village priests swam in the usually restricted pool of holy water. The priests wore a white robe for life, and were prohibited from doing certain things like cutting your hair and eating meat. Because the position of a priest was handed down by bloodline, you could only become priest when your father passed on. Therefore the priests were all pretty much at a ripe old age. And these priests had to swim in the pool of water with their robes, which apparently was extremely heavy even before being soaked in water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pool.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:440px; height:590px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One by one the priests in their white robes and emerged, marching in one line toward the water. You could tell that every pair of eyes were focused on the man at the front of the line, the priest who was first going to step into the pool. No one wanted to miss that defining moment when his fingertips would touch the water. Even I felt myself holding my breath. After a couple of times touching the water and sprinkling on his body, he plunged in, head first. Cheers erupted from every corner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/priest.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:440px; height:590px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then one by one the priests came down, each time accompanied by wild gasps and cheers of joy. Towards the end, an especially frail looking old man came down supported by two men. Looking at the way he was covered with wrinkles and his body looking so fragile, I didn’t think he would be able to make it into the water. Neither did the two men supporting him. But despite the protests from the two men, the old priest pushed them off and into the water he went. The younger men obviously looked distressed, but unable to chase him into the water because non-priests were only able to enter the water after the priests finished swimming. The festival could sometimes be dangerous, with the older people with weak immune systems exerting their body at such lengths. The old man’s action displayed just how special this event was to them, and not even their physical condition could stop them from diving in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once everything was complete it was time for the local people (only men though) to jump into the pool. It went absolutely wild with young men diving in from every corner. Look at Nirman go!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/jumping.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:330px; height:440px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a nice refreshing time full of colors, music and fresh unpolluted air of the village. I later heard that this festival might come to an end in the future, as villagers were beginning to protest against the priest’s prestige and the benefits they were receiving. This was because the younger priests were not abiding by some of the rules, like not wearing the white robe at all times or wearing underwear. This made me think about what culture and tradition really meant. Culture and tradition is not something that is completely stagnant over time. But change that comes blatantly would never be accepted as part of it. Personally it would be a little sad to see the tradition of the festival that embodied such unity and spirituality lost, in exchange for preserving tradition as people knew it. In a country where culture and tradition is so closely intertwined with daily life, it would be interesting to see how they can be adapted to modern day society, and where people will strictly put their foot down to draw the line.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/08/21/Festival-at-Nirman's-Village.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/08/21/Festival-at-Nirman's-Village.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Visit to CloudFactory</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There’s probably not a single person in Kathmandu interested in IT that doesn’t know CloudFactory. CloudFactory is one of the major international IT companies here in Kathmandu, and not only are they well known inside the country, but they are well recognized abroad too for their social mission. CloudFactory basically provides BPO (business process outsourcing) services through an API driven on-demand workforce. So what happens is, when foreign clients (businesses) hands them over their back end work, the parts that can be automated will be processed through tools that internal software developers developed, and the rest are divided into small micro tasks to be done manually. What’s cool about this is that these micro tasks like data entry are delegated to people all around Kathmandu - people who may not necessarily have high IT skills but are ready to work with their computers. CloudFactory has been able to provide employment to thousands of youth this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our encounter with CloudFactory is kind of a funny story actually. Last year when we first came up with the concept of TECHRISE, we did a simple google search “Ruby on Rails Nepal”. It seemed like this CloudFactory was the dominant, if not only, company using Rails. And this mega company seemed to have evolved from the same idea that we had – teaching Ruby on Rails to local Nepalese. When we clicked around the homepage some more, we saw that the head office was located in Durham – which was ten minutes away from where Take was studying at in North Carolina (We were both studying abroad in the US at the time). It felt like fate. We knew we had to go talk to them. So a couple of weeks later, we had our meeting set up at their office in a super cool startup hub complete with a slide. They were really nice cool guys, introduced us to Karmath the alpha of the Nepal operations, and fast forward to today we were meeting up with him and the CloudFactory team at their office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main purpose of our visit to CloudFactory today was to talk about the possible collaboration that we could have between CloudFactory and TECHRISE. Our first visit to CloudFactory – we were absolutely blown away. From the outside you couldn’t tell but the inside, it was buzzing with energy. Rows of wooden desks, multiple desktops and macs lying around, loads of mug cups…it looked like a startup you would see in the US. I immediately envisioned TECHRISE becoming like this giant operation. &lt;i&gt;The dream&lt;/i&gt;.
We had a great meeting on the rooftop with the developers that Karmath brought together. They were super nice, and offered to help us in things like looking over our curriculum and providing mentorship for the more advanced student later on. It was super exciting to think about the prospects of collaborating with a company like CloudFactory. We left the office in awe, and hopes that one-day we could be as large and vibrant as they were.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/cloudfactory.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Cloud Factory Vist&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After we returned we celebrated our team member Lakshman’s birthday! Lakshman has been amazing with all the marketing stuff  - reaching out to local media outlets, organizing events, pumping out blog content. There’s little detail that he misses, and is always there to remind us that there are gaps in our marketing schemes. The major reason why we have been gaining so much attention from around Kathmandu is definitely because of he’s doing. Even though we spend time together everyday, this was the first time we had some personal down time over some drinks. It was a lot of fun on the rooftop, as we just ate, drank and talked about the future of TECHRISE. Happy Birthday Lakshman!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/lakshmanbday.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Cloud Factory Vist&quot; style=&quot;width:330px; height:440px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/08/19/A-Visit-to-CloudFactory!.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/08/19/A-Visit-to-CloudFactory!.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What I learned So Far About Starting Up a Startup</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;What I learned about starting up a start up – week three in progress!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the four things I figured out about starting a start up in a foreign developing country so far. We’re only starting out so I’m sure I’ll be adding on to this later on!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;1.What you learn in books or in class means nothing!!&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Ok, I take that back. Yes it’s always important to dig deep into books, podcasts, attend seminars and so forth to gain some basic knowledge on how to run a business. But the truth is, that knowledge will only take you so far, and you never will &lt;i&gt;really get it&lt;/i&gt; until you begin. And when you are in a foreign country, you’ll probably diverge more than ever from what you studied because what ultimately matters most I think is the &lt;strong&gt;local context&lt;/strong&gt;. You can recite all the business terms and concepts in the world, but those aren’t the words used here in Nepal. &lt;i&gt;Nothing will work&lt;/i&gt; unless you adapt it to the way it’s done in this country. 
For example the day before we officially opened TECHRISE, we were having a cup of tea with our Nepali friends. They completely drilled us that evening and we realized that we knew nothing about Nepali style management. From how to deal with absences, tardiness, various holidays (some festival related holidays could lead up to weeks where people go back to their homes outside Kathmandu Valley), to the type of bonuses and incentives to keep everyone’s motivation high – they made us realize that &lt;i&gt;we had no clue&lt;/i&gt; about how things were done here. We went back to our rooms, re-assessed everything and drafted out some rules we wanted to make clear. I imagine that we would have had a far more chaotic organization if we hadn’t done this. You can have some pre-conceived notions about how things should be done, but you would be surprised at how things actually work. I would say make your assumptions and base your decisions off the theories and best practices you learned, but when you do, do the way the locals do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;2.Build relationships, don’t just throw money at the problem&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What will take you far are the people around you. It makes sense to have a good relationship with your employees and everyone else directly related to your business, but what about those that aren’t? - &lt;i&gt;Just build a good relationship&lt;/i&gt;. Because problems like your pipe leaking, or your light suddenly going out are problems that are going to keep coming back. In a society where everything is so tight knit and communal, the way to get things done is to “call a guy”. Or a guy who knows a guy. So try to build a good relationship with whomever you interact with, whether they may seem to be relevant to your business or not. Don’t just try to close the deal with money, because most likely you will be encountering them again and again. Even when you buy your fruits or veggies from the local market, get to know them. Once you’re on good terms with them, they will reduce the price of your merchandise or sometimes give you a little something extra. It can be small little things like this, but it will definitely eliminate your daily stress and brighten up your day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;3.The concept of time is radically different from yours&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you think startup, you may imagine the team working blood and sweat around the clock. Every second matters, and the success of your business depends on the time you devote to it. We feel the exact same way sometimes, and want to just keep working. BUT we know that it’s almost as equally important to have our daily evening tea with our friends who come by after work. The &lt;i&gt;hanging out&lt;/i&gt; part is crucial, because to them the time spent together (not necessarily doing anything) is valuable, and that’s what you do if you trust and love each other. Another thing is that &lt;i&gt;Nepali time&lt;/i&gt; is usually around 15 ~30 minutes later than the normal time on the clock, or even later sometimes. Totally different from Japan where we are strictly taught to be at least five minutes earlier than scheduled time. So, creating a culture of time management is super high on the list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;4.Listen – no, really&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t think you know better just because you went to some elite school, did some internships and took a class or two about business. Because you don’t. You will gain much more insights and will be able to make better decisions if you actually took the time to listen. Like I said above, you really want to adapt your marketing strategies, operations and all to be effective and appealing to the local people. You need to understand how people here react to certain messages and actions from the company. For example when we first opened up applications to enroll in TECHRISE in January, by the next day almost 40 people had signed up. Concerned that we wouldn’t be able to handle so many students in the beginning, I hastily decided to close down the application form. But later my team members urged me to keep them open longer, because their intuition told them that while many would be interested in this new foreign program, they were unlikely to actually complete the pre-work (necessary for admittance). True enough, out of the hundred that signed up only eight ended up completing the pre-work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this is a summary of what i’ve learned so far. Hope there were some things that you found interesting or could relate to! Let me know if you liked this post or not :)&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/08/18/What-I-learned-about-starting-up-a-startup.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/08/18/What-I-learned-about-starting-up-a-startup.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hello World!</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;hello-world&quot;&gt;Hello World!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess it&#39;s kind of tacky but since we are starting up a web dev related startup, I decided to use the most commonly used line ever for novice coders - Hello World. So, Hello World. I’ve finally decided to start my own blog about my daily doings and findings here in Nepal. It’s been a month since I started living here with my boyfriend Take, and everyday is really a new day. So much has happened, and things have been moving astonishingly fast with our startup TECHRISE. I hope this can be just a light read kind of blog where you can get a taste of the hustle-bustle life going on here. You can also check also out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.techrise.me/blog&quot;&gt;TECHRISE Blog&lt;/a&gt; which is a little bit more on a serious note. Comments would be greatly appreciated - it would really be a source of motivation for me to keep on writing and exploring:) &lt;br /&gt;
Since we are already one-month in, i’m going to give a quick run down what went on so far. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First Week:&lt;/strong&gt; Cleaning, buying, repairing — not everything, but A LOT. The carpet, tables, chairs, lights, fridge...wow, starting out a new life is costly.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Second Week:&lt;/strong&gt; Painted some walls. Did more cleaning and moving things around. Would not have done it without all our friends (and friends of friends). One work, one cup of tea. Repeat.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Third Week:&lt;/strong&gt; Officially launched TECHRISE on August 1st! Welcomed our first 8 students whom we selected from the pre work. Everyone is super excited, and some students are just raging through the course work.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Fourth Week:&lt;/strong&gt; TECHRISE picking up..? First paying customers as well as new user signups breaking record each day. Also we are starting to follow the routine of sleeping by 10pm and waking up by 6:30am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Other stuff that happened&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Things related to TECHRISE:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We held our first public event “How to Start Your Freelancing Career”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We were approached by a college out of the blue to speak at a conference and give training workshops at their college &lt;/li&gt;	
&lt;li&gt;We were featured in a couple of Neplali magazine outlets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apparently our biggest competitor is viewing us as a threat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pumping out work daily at the office with the four team members from one to five. Communication is mostly done via slack, even though we are sitting opposite from each other. Go home, continue communicating via slack.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Things not related to TECHRISE:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We literally drank more than a hundred cups of tea each&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We went to two birthday parties&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We went swimming in a local swimming pool (people spat a lot in it but it was still fun)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We went to a bar where they played metal and Nepali folk songs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I made Take dance, he was pretty bad &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I had a five minute conversation with the shop owner in Nepali, of which I understood about 60%. Progress! &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/08/16/First-Blog-Post.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/08/16/First-Blog-Post.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
