<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Natsuko&#39;s Blog</title>
    <description>Natsuko&#39;s Daily Adventures in Nepal</description>
    <link>http://naztshinozaki.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://naztshinozaki.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 10:37:15 +0545</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 10:37:15 +0545</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hello World!</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;hello-world&quot;&gt;Hello World!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess it&#39;s kind of tacky but since we are starting up a web dev related startup, I decided to use the most commonly used line ever for novice coders - Hello World. So, Hello World. I’ve finally decided to start my own blog about my daily doings and findings here in Nepal. It’s been a month since I started living here with my boyfriend Take, and everyday is really a new day. So many things have happened, and things have been moving astonishingly fast with our startup TECHRISE. I hope this can be just a light read kind of blog where you can get a taste of the hustle-bustle life going on here. You can also check also out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.techrise.me/blog&quot;&gt;TECHRISE Blog&lt;/a&gt; which is a little bit more on a serious note. Comments would be greatly appreciated - it would really be a source of motivation for me to keep on writing and exploring:) &lt;br /&gt;
Since we are already one-month in, i’m going to give a quick run down what went on so far. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First Week:&lt;/strong&gt; Cleaning, buying, repairing — not everything, but A LOT. The carpet, tables, chairs, lights, fridge...wow, starting out a new life is costly.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Second Week:&lt;/strong&gt; Painted some walls. Did more cleaning and moving things around. Would not have done it without all our friends (and friends of friends). One work, one tea. Repeat.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Third Week:&lt;/strong&gt; Officially launched TECHRISE on August 1st! Welcomed our first 8 students whom we selected from the pre work. Everyone is super excited, and some students are just raging through the course work.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Fourth Week:&lt;/strong&gt; TECHRISE picking up..? First paying customers as well as new user signups breaking record each day. Also we are starting to follow the routine of sleeping by 10pm and waking up by 6:30am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Other stuff that happened&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Things related to TECHRISE:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We held our first public event “How to Start Your Freelancing Career”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We were approached by a college out of the blue to speak at a conference and give training workshops at their college &lt;/li&gt;	
&lt;li&gt;We were featured in a couple of Neplali magazine outlets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apparently our biggest competitor is viewing us as a threat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pumping out work daily at the office with the four team members from one to five. Communication is mostly via slack, even though we are sitting opposite from each other. Go home, continue communicating via slack.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Things not related to TECHRISE:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We drank literally more than a hundred cups of tea each&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We went to two birthday parties&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We went swimming in a local swimming pool (people spat a lot in it but it was still fun)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We went to a bar where they played metal and Nepali folk songs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I made Take dance, he was pretty bad &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I had a five minute conversation with the shop owner in Nepali, of which I understood about 60%. Progress! &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/08/16/First-Blog-Post.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/08/16/First-Blog-Post.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
