<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Natsuko&#39;s Blog</title>
    <description>Natsuko&#39;s Daily Adventures in Nepal</description>
    <link>http://naztshinozaki.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://naztshinozaki.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2016 16:32:18 +0545</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2016 16:32:18 +0545</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Natsuko&#39;s mom in Nepal Part 2!</title>
        <description>My mom left last monday after her 10 day trip in Nepal. 
I’m so glad she was able to finally come to the country that i’ve been talking about non stop for 4 years now, and meet all the people who have been by my side since my first visit here. 
I was once again truly amazed and touched by everyone’s hospitality towards a complete foreigner who was just here for a short trip. My friends enthusiastically explained to her their history and culture, and made it a point to be part of her experience here in Nepal. I was comfortable enough to send her to Emerald English School in Chapagaun and to the massage therapist at edge of the city, because I knew there were reliable people waiting for her on the other end. Sure enough, my mom came back both times happy with new friends and new knowledge about Nepal.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;
One of the most memorable part of the second half of her trip was the hike at Telkot. 
We went for a day hiking trip with the TECHRISE gang to Telkot, which is located about 30 minutes away from Bhaktapur by bus. It was raining that morning, but we all met up at the Bhaktapur bus stop at 8:00 am. We ended up leisurely drinking tea, strolling around the famous water ponds, looking for something to eat because we realised that we needed food before going up, and then settling down to eat. When we finally made our way to Telkot, it was almost 11:00 pm. This doesn’t bother me one bit though, because &lt;i&gt;that’s how we roll in Nepal.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/telkot3.JPG&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:600px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/telkot9.JPG&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:600px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Once we were on higher grounds we found a tree that bore Lapsi, a fruit that apparently is only found in Nepal. It was usually eaten in a dried and seasoned form, as a pickle or candy. We picked some off the ground, and threw our shoes at the tree to shake more off. The fruit was still unripe, but the unique fleshiness and sourness of it was pleasing to suck on. 
&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/telkot1.JPG&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:600px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/telkot2.JPG&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:600px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
We went through the mountains for about 4,5 hours observing the different foliage and the occasional goats or dogs. The air was fresh and clean, unlike the dusty polluted roads down in the city. 
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/telkot5.JPG&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:600px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/telkot7.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:700px; height:200px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The hike ended at Changu Narayan, the oldest temple in Nepal. The oldest inscription on the stone pillar was dated back to 464 AD. These aged carvings had been through countless changes in society, and fluctuations in climate - no wonder there was an ancient majestic feel to the place that could not be ignored. It’s astonishing how people in the ancient times were so advanced in their skills, and dedicated to creating so many of these temples and monuments.
I was extremely tired from all the walking which I wasn’t used to, but it was definitely a change of scenery for our daily lives.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/telkot6.JPG&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:600px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/telkot8.JPG&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:600px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
On my mom’s last day Neekesh, Sabina, and the rest of the gang threw her a surprise farewell party with a cake! I was touched, and so was my unexpecting mom too i’m sure. We enjoyed our last evening with laughter and home cooked Japanese food on the terrace.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/mom2-1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:600px; height:440px; &quot;&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;
To some, a trip to Nepal may be just a fleeting moment, a mere destination out of the many possible expedition around the world. But somehow I see many people being drawn back here. I think it’s something about the people, something about the majestic temples and buildings among the overly crowded dusty roads that calls people back to Kathmandu.
I hope that my mom also feels the same - that someday she would want to come back again, to walk the streets by the temples, to have the sugary cups masala tea, and to greet those who welcomed her with open arms. 
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/mom2-2.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:600px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Mom looking sad at the airport.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;br&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Bye mom, see you again soon!&lt;/i&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/09/27/Mom-in-Nepal2.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/09/27/Mom-in-Nepal2.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Natsuko&#39;s mom in Nepal!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Natsuko’s mom in Nepal!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My daily schedule has been definitely different these days. That’s because my mom – Monica Shinozaki is here for the first time in Nepal!
I have been bugging her to come to Nepal and she’s finally decided to come all the way from Japan!
So I’ve been pretty busy bringing her hear and there, revisiting the tourists sights I went to 4 years ago when I first came. I realized that ever since Take and I have arrived, 2months ago we have literally not done any form of sight seeing. It’s been great refreshment, seeing Nepal with a new pair of eyes and eating some good food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To give a quick overview of the past couple of days…&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Day 1&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
In the morning we went to the almighty tourist location in Kathmandu – Thamel! I generally avoid the Kathmandu side (we are located in Lalitpur, a district right next to Kathmandu) because it feels much dustier and somewhat unfamiliar, but I took a step outside of my comfort zone to bring her around the city. 
Change 1 (from my daily life): Get out of Lalitpur (out of our house for that matter). 
Followed immediately by, 
Change 2: Travel by Taxi. 
I’m usually willing to pay 15 ~30 Nepalese Rupees (approx. 15 ~30 cents) for my transportation on a public vehicle. 300 NPR for the same distance? Pfffttt. PLEASE. The ride was a lot more comfortable though. A LOT MORE. 
Anyways, in Thamel we went around hunting for the shawls, the crafts, the jewelries, and all the other artisan products. Each shop has something special, and they really are not the same in every store. We found a store that had some really beautiful paper crafts like lampshades, ornaments and calendars. We even found a kettle coaster made out of small woolen balls. A random, solitary piece, but we impulsively decided to get it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/furry.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:330px; width:450px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the evening we went to the charity event for my host brother’s NGO (he was my host brother 4 years ago): Help to Needy Children. It was a live music event at a restaurant bar, and we had so much fun! We loved all the Nepali songs played by the local band. Everyone from young to old was dancing and having a blast with the hit numbers. I was able to put into good use the dance moves I learnt during Teej.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/party.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:600px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 2&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Take’s Birthday Breakfast at our favorite Café!
Change 3:  Having actual FOOD at the café - not just coffee. 
Poor expats that we are, we usually just order coffee. But this time we had some gorgeous breakfast food! Thank you mom! I’m not used to eating so much in the morning anymore, I was slightly giddy by the end of the meal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/soma1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:600px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the evening we went to see a Western and Nepali fusion Opera “Arjuna’s Dilenma”.  Produced by the One Young World Theaters, this kind of fusion opera was the first of its kind in Nepal. The production was at the courtyard of the Patan Museum, and it was beautiful with the temples looming in the background. The museum itself is an old majestic building with intricate carvings on the wood and decorated with sturdy looking bronze pieces. The Opera was amazing too – there was traditional music, Jazz, a women choir group, a sax player, a ballet dancer, and all sorts of other performing art forms to depict the scenes and emotions set around Krishna and Arjun. I was spell bound for the whole 70 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 3&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
It was raining the whole day today! So my mother decided to take initiative to do some volunteer work here. 
Change 4: Innovation in the Kitchen 
She took it upon herself to renovate the whole kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/mom.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:300px; height:400px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She pulled out all the 100 yen shop supplies that I brought here previously and totally reformed the place. She organized everything in different compartments, set up racks to hang up thing, put curtains to cover up the storage, and even placed some styrohfome lying around on the wall for a funky touch. I didn’t think my kitchen was so bad before but now looking at the transformation I was blown away. This was true innovation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the evening we went to Mangal Bazaar. We walked inside the square and did a whole big round going through the small alleyways. Mangal Bazaar is one of my favorite places, because people’s lives were so closely integrated with the ancient buildings and temples. People simply sat around them watching the world go by, or would buy some things at the small stores that dominated the street side. It’s not the case where the temples are strictly restricted to it being a tourist spot, and people’s daily lives being something else. They co-existed, and I loved that atmosphere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/mangal.JPG&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:600px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The nice thing about shopping at these local stores in Nepal is that people don’t really try to rip tourists off. There are comparatively less people who demand for a exorbitant price, and they don’t really push you into buying things. I can hold a friendly conversation, learn about them and the products before deciding to make a purchase. And that generally works, because we feel more inclined to by it then simply walking away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The adventures to be continued!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/09/15/Mom-in-Nepal.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/09/15/Mom-in-Nepal.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Teej - Fasting for the First Time!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I got to experience my first &lt;strong&gt;Teej&lt;/strong&gt;, the largest women’s festival in Nepal! Teej is a celebration where women gather together to fast for the longevity and health of their husbands, worship at the temples and dance. My Nepali sister Depa first told me about this festival four years ago, and she was super excited when she knew that I would be here during this time. In fact, that was one of the first things she exclaimed about - that I would finally be able to celebrate Teej with her - when I said that I would be staying in Nepal for the whole year. &lt;strong&gt;This was something I could not miss&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all started with my dress picking for the day, about a week ago. Two of my friends brought me out to shop for the perfect garment for the occasion. In the small Sari shop that I was brought to in Mangal Bazar (I honestly don’t know how people find these stores in the nook and crooks of the street), I was thrown a whole array of options. &lt;i&gt;Choosing these garments are an intense matter&lt;/i&gt;. I tried them on, one after another. After much prodding, twirling, and tightening of the loose cloth on my body, we settled on a blue and orange Lehenga. After that we also went to pick out the shoes, accessories, and fixed the Lehenga at the tailor shop -  all with deliberate contemplation. Then finally I was set for the day.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Teej this year fell on Sunday. So from Saturday evening, I went over to Depa’s house and enjoyed a feast of all kinds of delicious dishes and sweets. All Depa’s relatives from young to old, we  all pre-danced in our pyjamas. We went pretty wild, thrusting out our moves to the music from the cell phone. We ate again at 11 pm, just before it turned the next day when we had to begin our fast. I was not very hungry but I helped myself to the late night feast of coconut and almond mixed rice, yogurt, and some traditional sweets. I was full to the max but still ate because I was pretty nervous about feeling hungry the next day.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/teej6.JPG&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:600px;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up not hungry, but still I was a bit worried about how I could go through the day without drinking any water or food till sunset. But the purpose of the festival wasn’t endurance, so I tried to brush the thought out of my head and enjoy the day. We got up and began preparing for our visit to the temple, which basically meant putting on lots of make up. I’ve never put on so much makeup, but it felt pretty great having myself- beautified and being told that I look like a Nepali girl (um, girl?!). The temple was a vibrant color of red and green with the beautifully embroided Saris. Look at these beauties! &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/teej5.JPG&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:600px;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/teej1.JPG&quot; style=&quot;height:330px; width:450px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/teej2.JPG&quot; style=&quot;height:330px; width:450px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/teej3.JPG&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:600px;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok I’m going to spill the beans but I was not able to do a full fasting that day. After becoming all hot and sweaty from dancing, I gave into drinking water. I swear I could have endured it but when some of my friends drank some water, I just couldn’t resist. I abstained from eating food till sunset though. I never imagined that it was be so hard, I felt pretty dizzy and low on energy by 3pm. Again it’s probably because I wasn’t entirely fasting for a purpose, I was fasting more for formality. Depa always used to tell me that the days she fasts she never feels hungry, but instead feels good from the purity of what she is doing and the holiness associated with it. It was an interesting experience to fast, putting myself in the shoes of so many others who fast as part of their religion. The act definitely takes a toll on the body. But the beliefs associated now I see now is &lt;i&gt;so powerful and meaningful&lt;/i&gt; to those who practice it, that it is far more gratifying than satisfying the immediate needs of your body. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I had my first bite of the milky sweets at 5pm, I felt the sugar in it flowing through my blood and nourishing my body. &lt;i&gt;I felt revitalized&lt;/i&gt;. I was amazed at how that little piece could give me so much energy.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/teej7.JPG&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:600px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I came back for the night, but I will be returning back again tomorrow for another full day of dancing in the temple. I’m super grateful to Depa and her family for inviting me to be part of their family festivities, and Nepali culture. I loved all the colors and the joy in the air, and i’m definitely looking forward tomorrow for another day of dancing and fun (and this time food!). 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/teej8.JPG&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:600px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/09/05/Teej.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/09/05/Teej.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Our First 30 Day Sprint</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been &lt;i&gt;a month&lt;/i&gt; since we officially launched TECHRISE in Nepal. The days have flown by super quickly but it has certainly been a fruitful couple of weeks. To mark this first month, I’d like to reflect over our accomplishments (keeping things positive here!) and some things we would be focusing on going forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To sum up our first month, more than reaching our goals as a company, I think our success would be defined in terms of the of initial &lt;strong&gt;&lt;i&gt;“company culture”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; we created. Although I think that company culture is super important, it’s not so easy when there are geography based cultures that we have to consider first. Trying to understand the ways and values that we each grew up with, is vital in making things work in all spectrums of the business. &lt;i&gt;Company culture&lt;/i&gt; is what will be ultimately handed down, and is what I believe will help propel us forward through the various changes we would go through over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of these &lt;i&gt;cultural&lt;/i&gt; things that we cultivated I think is the &lt;strong&gt;experiment and go&lt;/strong&gt; mentality. We tested and changed so many things over the past 30 days -  from the wording of the “call to action” button on the landing page, to our strategies on how we approach potential students. We could list a bunch of things that we implemented, and they would all be things that we never thought would exist a month ago. Like I said before in my blog posts on &lt;a href=&quot;https://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/08/24/Stand-Up-Meetings.html&quot;&gt;stand up meetings&lt;/a&gt;, the constant loop of experimentation  and iteration I think is what helps us determine what is working and what doesn’t. Everyone on the team shoots out ideas, and we try them out as &lt;strong&gt;quickly&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;cost effectively&lt;/strong&gt; as possible. For example if we run facebook ads, we would test it out with a small budget first before launching a longer campaign, or if we want to hold events, we would first present to our current students and get feedback before going public (we did 4 events this month - &lt;a href=&quot;https://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/08/26/Freelancing-Event-Round-2.html&quot;&gt;“How to Start Your Freelancing Career”&lt;/a&gt; and a “Blogging with Jekyll” workshop).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another positive I think is that we’re beginning to realise the &lt;strong&gt;communal aspect&lt;/strong&gt; as one of the intergrel values of TECHRISE. The intimacy between the students and the mentors, as well as between the students themselves, is really what fosters a group identity that keeps them motivated. It also helps that they are a pretty high quality and driven bunch to begin with, since they were pre-screened through some assignments before being admitted. Hands down to Take and Aadesh for the great mentor-student relationship, they have been answering students questions on slack and facebook almost 24/7. And trust me they get &lt;i&gt;a lot of questions&lt;/i&gt;. The students regard themselves as part of the TECHRISE family, and it’s great because they actively help one another out, and they are the walking proof that TECHRISE is a working model. This small tight-knit community will not be the same as we expand, but I think part of the challenge in the future is how we can maintain this closeness with a much larger and diverse group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going forward, there are a couple of things that we want to focus, especially in the upcoming month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Educating ourselves on our respective roles&lt;/strong&gt; – We have our respective roles: Take and Aadesh are mentors and platform developers, while Lakshman and I take on more of the business and marketing side of TECHRISE. In the past week we purchased some resources - &lt;i&gt;Upcase&lt;/i&gt; for further learning Ruby on Rails, and &lt;i&gt;Code School&lt;/i&gt; for some web design stuff (they were doing a great promotion). We also dug up some online free certification courses like &lt;i&gt;Hubspot&lt;/i&gt; marketing courses. Other than our day to day operations, we will be taking some time boosting our skills up so that we can really excel at what we do.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Understanding our potential students and making more data driven decisions&lt;/strong&gt; – We are now getting a better picture of who are attracted to the things we do at TECHRISE, and who our mission speaks to most.  Identifying the specific needs of our potential clients and illustrating them as &lt;i&gt;audience personas&lt;/i&gt; would help us deliver contents that are on point. We are currently no master at analyzing data, but we really need to start deeply examining our analytics to determine our next moves.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reaching out directly to students&lt;/strong&gt; - Along with understanding our customer base, we also want to start directly approaching students. Up till now we have relied mostly on facebook marketing and some interaction with students through our workshop events. Going to schools and meetups would give us a chance to find out more about who they are and what they want. We think that there are many more people out there that would benefit from TECHRISE, but they just aren’t familiar with the bootcamps concept or about Ruby on Rails.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This frst month really was a sprint, but September probably would be no different. It will be a long time more before we can enter the jogging phase. We’re all enjoying ourselves though, and waking up each day cannot be more exciting ;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/09/05/First-month.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/09/05/First-month.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Gap Between the Job Market and Higher Education in the IT Field</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After stuffing ourselves, we returned back to the office to host our small discussion session event at TECHRISE. We invited a couple of startup guys, web developers and some college administrators. The purpose of the session was to discuss about the existing gap between the &lt;strong&gt;job market and higher education in the IT field&lt;/strong&gt;. I wanted to bring to one table these people who all worked in this field but in various spaces, to have a frank and open discussion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/discussion1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:590px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through our nearly two-hour conversation we realized that the gap that we were trying to identify was not only limited to simply the gap between what is required by the job market and what is being taught at the educational institutions. There were multiple so-called &lt;i&gt;gaps&lt;/i&gt;, which all came into play to create this disparity and disconnect. Some of these gaps that we identified were:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The gap between the &lt;i&gt;demands from the &lt;strong&gt;industry&lt;/strong&gt; (wants experienced and qualified individuals) and the &lt;strong&gt;students&lt;/strong&gt; (do not have any experience and very little qualifications)&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The gap between the &lt;i&gt;skills students acquire and what is required from the job market&lt;/i&gt; – Many of the concepts and content are outdated and not in demand&lt;/li&gt;


&lt;li&gt;The gap between the &lt;i&gt;talent the students wish to supply and the demand from the market&lt;/i&gt; - There are not enough industries that are monetizable. People cannot make a living unless you are working in a highly in demand sector (not limited to the IT sector)&lt;/li&gt; &lt;br /&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/discussion2.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:590px;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other interesting points that came up were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The lack of motivation among students – perhaps linked to the fact that there are limited opportunities to see how what they learned can be applied to the real world&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The importance of students nurturing a problem solving attitude, instead of a passive learning one&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The culture of &lt;i&gt;blame&lt;/i&gt;: students blaming teachers for not being able to understand and perform, and vice versa teachers blaming students&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were so many factors that were interrelated to constructing this discrepancy. The conversation is a never-ending one with no real conclusion. But from the discussion, I think we came to realize that there are two roles that we can take on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.	To inspire the students to apply their skills to the real world, and motivate them to pursue further with academics at school &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.	Help them become real problem solvers through curriculum design (you can learn more about the TECHRISE learning system though this  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.techrise.me/posts/how-techrise-creates-superstar-coders&quot;&gt;  blog &lt;/a&gt;) and providing more opportunities to work on real live projects &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an educational entity that really cares about doing what’s best for the students and their learning, we found everyone’s insights extremely valuable. Their willingness to sacrifice a Saturday afternoon to hold this conversation really showed their passion towards what they did in this field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a long day for us but a really meaningful weekend!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/08/28/Discussion-Event.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/08/28/Discussion-Event.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>8th NasCOIT Keynote Speech</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Saturday was another hectic day full of events. 
First of all there was the 8th National Student Conference on Information Technology - one of the most prestigious IT related events o the year. I’m not sure how they found us or why they decided to approach us, but about 3 weeks ago, the organizer of this event suddenly contacted us. Their invitation to deliver the keynote speech was all so abrupt with their sudden appearance at our office door, we simply said yes. 
So to be honest we were really not expecting the kind of grandeur that awaited us at the venue. The conference was held at a famous five star hotel in Kathmandu, the Yak and Yeti Hotel. &lt;i&gt;Boy was it grand&lt;/i&gt;. It was a huge, almost palace like building with well-groomed bellboys, guards and everything. The inside was gorgeous and even air-conditioned! When we saw the crowd all suited up, we immediately regretted our attire. Not that we had much of a choice I guess though. Take was wearing slacks and his best polo, while I was wearing the only skirt I had brought. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/NaSCoIT1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:590px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The morning session in which Take delivered the short speech mostly ended with remarks from the organizers / important seniors involved. He talked about the importance of blending in technology (e-learning models) with the human factor that supplements the learning. As a final message, he implored the audience to consider developing the educational field through technology in Nepal as IT professionals. &lt;strong&gt; While there are so many outstanding e-learning type of innovations out there in the world, they cannot be directly imported to Nepal without adapting it to the Nepali context and curriculum. &lt;/strong&gt; I think there is loads of potential especially in Nepal where there are so many different kinds of edcational challenges. But again I suppose that it is necessary to construct an &lt;i&gt;incentive system&lt;/i&gt; where people are rewarded for their efforts in developing the educational sector. Without proper monitary incentives, I think it’s highly unlikely that the brightest minds will divert their time and effort there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/NasCoIT2.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:440px; height:590px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had to hurry back right after lunch so unfortunately we weren’t able to hear a bunch of student presentations, which was the highlight of the event. The lunch was amazing by the way. It was a delicious buffet with different kind of salads, curries and desserts. I think our enthusiasm towards the food was a little too much, as we devoured our first plate in minutes and headed back for seconds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The afternoon discussion event held at TECHRISE will be continued in the next blog post :) Lot of interesting findings on what’s actually happening at the industry level and the educational level.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/08/28/8th-NaSCoIT.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/08/28/8th-NaSCoIT.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Freelancing Event Round 2</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today we held our second public seminar on “How to Start Your Freelancing Career” at TECHRISE. The last time we decided to hold the same seminar, which was two weeks ago, more than 70 people registered to attend. We ended up having to select only 30 due to the limited space in our office. Seeing that it was a great hit, we decided to hold a second round of the same seminar. This time too, we got over a 130 sign ups so we just decided to go for two sessions in one day. I suppose we should have closed the form earlier, but we were just curious to see how many would respond!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason why we came to choose this topic was because both Take and I have had quite a lot of experience freelancing as a part time job. I mostly translate, while Take has recently been taking on more web development projects. We discovered freelancing about two years ago, with a Japanese freelancing platform. &lt;i&gt;It was a total game changer for us.&lt;/i&gt; Initially it was hard getting projects with the competition, but eventually we were able to get more gigs as we experimented with our profile and our approaches to clients. After playing around with different ways to market ourselves, we began to earn quite a nice amount of pocket money. We were even able to earn back our travelling expense for our vacation by working a couple hours a day during that vacation (we still had fun, honestly!). We became workaholics in a way, but we loved the freedom of being able to work from anywhere, and doing as much or as less as we wished to. I honestly wouldn’t have been able to gain the experiences I have had so far, or even come to Nepal if I wasn’t backed up financially with what I earned from freelancing. Some of the tactics that we used in freelancing worked like magic, and once we got hold of it, things came pretty easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So our presentation was mostly around the tips and tricks we accumulated over the couple of years. I hope people found it useful – I mean, I certainly wish someone could have told me some of these things when we first started off! 31 participants turned up in each session, and the room was packed with human bodies. Mostly IT students, as well as some professional designers and web developers came out today. Even some who were currently working were interested because apparently they couldn’t really make it just by working for their company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/freelance2.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:590px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having two sessions in a day was pretty tough, but it was a lot of fun interacting with the participants during and after the presentation. Besides, in between presentations Lakshman and Aadesh ordered Momos so that we would get that oily energy boost ;) 
Some seemed to be genuinely interested in what we do at TECHRISE. I hope we were able to get some TECHRISE fans though this event!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/freelance1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:590px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/08/26/Freelancing-Event-Round-2.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/08/26/Freelancing-Event-Round-2.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Refreshing Morning at Soma Cafe</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I’ve been slightly restless. I’m not sure why but I’m guessing bits of fatigue and from being cooped up in the office too much. I love our building because we wake up, go down to the office to work, go up on the terrace to eat, and go even down to hang out with friends at the restaurant in the evening. But after following the routine of going up and down the flights of stairs daily, I wanted to have a bit of a change and spend a morning nice café. And have some good coffee that I have been missing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So after waking up, instead of going straight up to our kitchen we got changed and grabbed a tempo on the main road. Tempos are small open busses that are super convenient for short rides because you can basically stop anywhere you ask them to if its along the way. The drive up was only about 5 minutes – a much shorter ride than usual because the roads were super empty. Taking public transport was the hassle I usually didn’t enjoy, there were always too many people and the heat could really fry you. The ride today was sweet and short though, with a slight breeze coming in from the back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’m at Café Soma now, a café popular among the expat community. We came here twice before, on two special occasions where we met Karmath from Cloud Factory and Jeremiah who was also developing an online curriculum for coding. On both occasions we had a great time talking for well over two and a half hours, so the place was associated with good conversations and positive energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The atmosphere reminded me somewhat of DC, which I spent a school year in last year as an exchange student. Meetings were being held everywhere, and from each table you could catch snippets of really passionate people discussing some important sounding stuff. A lot like DC, where every coffee shop I went to some policy makers, government officials, large international organization personnel were huddled brewing up some impressive schemes. Sometimes I would pretend I’m doing my homework while really listening in on some game changing plans that were being made next to me. Café Soma had something similar in its atmosphere, buzzing with conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/soma2.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:590px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We ordered coffees and a muffin. Coffee. We’ve been drinking instant coffee, and compared to that the coffee here was on a whole new level. I’m not a coffee fanatic but after picking up the habit of drinking some over-priced coffee in DC last year, I’ve come to enjoy a good cup of brewed coffee. The chocolate chip muffin I ordered wasn’t bad either. Not as great as the calorie packed pastries that I gorged on so much, but one of the best ones I had here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also picked up a book at a near by bookstore called “Fatalism and Development – Nepal’s struggle for modernization”, written by a Nepalese anthropologist. Jeremiah recommended the book and it seems super interesting – right on point where my interest lies. The shopkeeper Bipin also recommended us a couple more about Nepal’s history, social issues and politics. I can’t wait to read all of them but I’m going to go one by one so I can have something to look forward to. The books here in Nepal are super cheap too apparently because they are printed in India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/book.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:300px; height:400px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The morning was a nice refresher from our daily schedule. It was so enjoyable that I think this is going to turn out to be a weekly routine!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/08/25/A-Refreshing-Morning-at-Soma-Cafe.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/08/25/A-Refreshing-Morning-at-Soma-Cafe.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Stand-Up Meetings</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Glancing up at the calendar it surprises me that we are still into our third week since officially launching TECHRISE. I’m not saying that we have been so successful that we can’t believe our achievements over the past third weeks. Rather, we are surprised at how much we have been able to progress based on our un-successes we have had. TECHRISE is not what it was a week ago, neither is it what it was a day before. I think we have been doing a pretty good job evolving daily, adapting and responding to the daily needs of our students and the market. The reason we are able to do this? I would attribute it most to out daily &lt;strong&gt;Stand-Up meetings&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stand-Up meetings are short meetings daily that many start-ups and agile software developments adopt. They are intended to be &lt;i&gt;short&lt;/i&gt; – short enough that people can do it while their standing up, hence the name Stand-up meetings. We use this method too, and what we do is go around the table each simply saying a couple of sentences on&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; 1. What you have been working on&lt;br /&gt;
2. What you are going to work on today &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it. These are the two things we recite during our 5-minute meetings. No fuss and no lengthy discussions on this and that.&lt;br /&gt;
This method is amazing because:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4 id=&quot;it-forces-you-to-move-on-with-tasks-and-keeps-you-accountable&quot;&gt;It forces you to move on with tasks and keeps you accountable&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You certainly don’t want to be saying that you have been working on xx task for three consecutive days - that would be awkward.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4 id=&quot;it-helps-you-understand-who-has-been-working-on-what&quot;&gt;It helps you understand who has been working on what&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It helps us communicate the progress made on the marketing team (Lakshman and Natsuko) and the developer team (Take and Aadesh) especially because we don’t work together so often.  It also opens doors to ways in which we can help each other.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4 id=&quot;it-helps-set-the-mood-for-the-day&quot;&gt;It helps set the mood for the day&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It puts you on the go mode!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other than our daily meetings, another way we keep in check what we have been doing individually as well as a team is by writing &lt;strong&gt;weekly logs&lt;/strong&gt;. Basically each Sunday we write in a Google Spread Sheet &lt;strong&gt;1. What was good about TECHRISE that week, 2. What needs improvements, 3. What kind of personal growth you had.&lt;/strong&gt; This really helps us get a more birds eye view on how TECHRISE is doing, and helps us create actionable goals for the week. The personal growth part I wanted to add in because I wanted everyone to feel his or her personal development through being involved in TECHRISE. I think this would be useful when the organization is in dooms day, because we can always look back and say &lt;i&gt;“Hey, at least we learned something”&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Growing up in Japan, I’ve often found my self in long dreary meetings where frankly I didn’t find was really going anywhere. The &lt;strong&gt;5-minute Stand-Up meetings &lt;/strong&gt;as well as our &lt;strong&gt;weekly logs&lt;/strong&gt; have been doing wonders for me though! I highly recommend this to any startup or organization if they aren’t already using this method. It’s life changing :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/08/24/Stand-Up-Meetings.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/08/24/Stand-Up-Meetings.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Festival at Nirman&#39;s Village</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday we went to a festival at our good friend Nirman and Saru’s village. They had been talking about this festival since the time we arrived here a month ago, so there was no way we were not going. 
Upon arriving at the village center, we could immediately tell that something special was about to happen. People filled every nook and corner of the square, and faces poked out of every window. This was a village festival held annually, a tradition of around 600 years where the village priests swam in the usually restricted pool of holy water. The priests wore a white robe for life, and were prohibited from doing certain things like cutting your hair and eating meat. Because the position of a priest was handed down by bloodline, you could only become priest when your father passed on. Therefore the priests were all pretty much at a ripe old age. And these priests had to swim in the pool of water with their robes, which apparently was extremely heavy even before being soaked in water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pool.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:440px; height:590px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One by one the priests in their white robes and emerged, marching in one line toward the water. You could tell that every pair of eyes were focused on the man at the front of the line, the priest who was first going to step into the pool. No one wanted to miss that defining moment when his fingertips would touch the water. Even I felt myself holding my breath. After a couple of times touching the water and sprinkling on his body, he plunged in, head first. Cheers erupted from every corner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/priest.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:440px; height:590px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then one by one the priests came down, each time accompanied by wild gasps and cheers of joy. Towards the end, an especially frail looking old man came down supported by two men. Looking at the way he was covered with wrinkles and his body looking so fragile, I didn’t think he would be able to make it into the water. Neither did the two men supporting him. But despite the protests from the two men, the old priest pushed them off and into the water he went. The younger men obviously looked distressed, but unable to chase him into the water because non-priests were only able to enter the water after the priests finished swimming. The festival could sometimes be dangerous, with the older people with weak immune systems exerting their body at such lengths. The old man’s action displayed just how special this event was to them, and not even their physical condition could stop them from diving in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once everything was complete it was time for the local people (only men though) to jump into the pool. It went absolutely wild with young men diving in from every corner. Look at Nirman go!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/jumping.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:330px; height:440px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a nice refreshing time full of colors, music and fresh unpolluted air of the village. I later heard that this festival might come to an end in the future, as villagers were beginning to protest against the priest’s prestige and the benefits they were receiving. This was because the younger priests were not abiding by some of the rules, like not wearing the white robe at all times or wearing underwear. This made me think about what culture and tradition really meant. Culture and tradition is not something that is completely stagnant over time. But change that comes blatantly would never be accepted as part of it. Personally it would be a little sad to see the tradition of the festival that embodied such unity and spirituality lost, in exchange for preserving tradition as people knew it. In a country where culture and tradition is so closely intertwined with daily life, it would be interesting to see how they can be adapted to modern day society, and where people will strictly put their foot down to draw the line.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/08/21/Festival-at-Nirman's-Village.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/08/21/Festival-at-Nirman's-Village.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
