<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Natsuko&#39;s Blog</title>
    <description>Natsuko&#39;s Daily Adventures in Nepal</description>
    <link>http://naztshinozaki.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://naztshinozaki.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 17:53:17 +0545</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 17:53:17 +0545</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Reflection of &#39;Moving Asia&#39; - Photo Kathmandu</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I had the opportunity to attend a panel discussions titled  &lt;em&gt;“Moving Asia”&lt;/em&gt; -  a dialogue surrounding migration in South Asia through the eyes of photojournalists. This panel discussion was among the many events held throughout the week as part of the Photo Kathmandu initiative, the only international photography festival in Nepal. Throughout this 14 day long festival, there were photo exhibitions in various venues around the city, and different talks, workshops, slideshows were being organised, all with the intent to spur a conversation between the locals and the visual storytellers.  I attended the session today, eager to learn how contemporary migration in South Asia was perceived and comprehended by local journalists. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/photoktm.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:600px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2016 was a year that sparked up much debate on the “Global Migration Crisis”. I was among the many others who watched from the safety of their homes, the horror unraveling as civilians endured unimaginable journeys risking their lives to flee their country, only to be met most of the time by unwelcoming faces on the other end. The migration crisis that sprung up mostly in the middle east, has largely affected some of the other major political events this year, such as the presidential campaign of the US and the BREXIT of the UK.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story that was told today however, was not those of the refugees who were fleeing from war or terrorism. Rather, they were stories of &lt;em&gt;economic migrants&lt;/em&gt;. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The three panelists each highlighted different aspects of South Asian migration, bringing to us new perspectives to reflect on. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first panelist displayed his work on images of migrants who mysteriously disappeared overseas, and their desperate family trying to look for them. The story of one vanishing while overseas is not uncommon. Possibilities were, that that person had died from some unsettling reason, or was in dire conditions in which they could not even access a phone. I recalled an incident that occurred a few years back, when my grandparent’s domestic helper in Singapore, received a sudden phone call that her brother had fallen off from a building he was helping construct in Dubai. Setting aside the fact there probably was an obvious safety hazard issue at play, this brother could easily have been a &lt;em&gt;“missing migrant”&lt;/em&gt;, an incident swept under the carpet in a far away land.  Other reasons for the sudden disappearance could be because the channel of communication was lost, perhaps with the change of a phone number. It was however, not always painful and tragic stories. &lt;br /&gt;
Controversy to the fear we sketch up in our minds when we hear that these individuals go missing, there are cases yet where it’s the individual choice not to be found. They may have settled with a family, and decided to leave behind their history and build up a new life. “Missing migrants” as the panelist put it, could come in so many forms, and the family’s wish for their child or spouse to return, was not always aligned with what the individual wanted for themselves. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second panelist highlighted the situation of women migration. The image people had of women leaving the country, was most commonly related to sex work. Therefore, the social stigma attached to them made it difficult for women to publicly announce their departure, or that they were currently abroad. Most women would just say they were going for work in  Kathmandu. It was not always the case that women were exploited into the sex industry though. From what the panelist found, some were thriving in a tailoring factory in Jordan, and living a satisfactory life. However, the women could not let people in their village know about the positive aspects from fear of discrimination - a degrading dichotomy between reality and the societal expectations towards women. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last panelist’s work was focused around Bangladeshi migrants in Malaysia. His words hit me deeply, and unexpectedly. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;“Economic migration is often seen as something unfavorable (by the host country). But sometimes it’s the only chance for one to radically turn around they’re life”&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;
People did not have the power to make the decision of where to be born. If you thought about it, it did seem almost selfish; how we desperately protected our borders, ruthlessly kicking out those that didn’t belong, when we don’t even have control over where we come out in this world. Was it really right to condemn those who only come to contribute, and to earn a wage to support their family? Free economic activity across borders may be taking it to the extreme, but do we have to shun away and belittle migrants like we do, treating them inferior to &lt;em&gt;citizens&lt;/em&gt; of the country? By going through the various pictures of the migration journey, this journalist was humanizing the process, reminding us (probably mostly foreigners who were not from South Asia) that these migrants were just…&lt;em&gt;people&lt;/em&gt;. There were so many ways we could relate to them, because in the end, they were just people.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This session made me realise that the story of humankind, sadly still flooded with agony and desperation, has to be actively told. When I say stories, I mean &lt;em&gt;stories of individuals&lt;/em&gt;, not just a collection of people we compress into data. We are so immune to the numbers already - how many millions and billions suffering, dying, and migrating around the world? Somehow we have become numb to the numbers we see and hear on our daily news. Perhaps we can’t fathom the fact that they are actually figures of people, maybe we are automatically stretching out a filter on our minds because we don’t want to believe it.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is why we need to shed more light onto the story of individual human beings. Especially with some of the issues concerning human rights that often get silenced, because the wealthy and powerful benefit from the exploitation. This is the only way we can become more compassionate, and see the &lt;em&gt;other&lt;/em&gt; not as something isolated from our world, but another human being that shares the same pains, hopes and dreams ourselves. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have my deepest respect to the stories and the unique media that the photographers brought forth today. Thank you for putting a human face on these issues that we see as only issues, a phenomena that we treat and deal with just as a phenomenon. &lt;br /&gt;
It is now our responsibility to share this human story with others. &lt;br /&gt;
If we can all really look at people as people, I imagine the world would be a better place.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/10/23/Photo-Kathmanu.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/10/23/Photo-Kathmanu.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Happy Dashain!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week were on a week long Dashain holiday, the largest holiday in Nepal. Dashain, also known as Vijaya Dashami, celebrates the “triumph over evil”, commemorating the victory of gods over the demons. The goddess Durga, who played an instrumental role in the battle between Lord Ram against the wicked demon Ravana in the famous story, is especially worshiped during this time. The festival lasts for 15 days, and usually for a couple of days during the most important dates, all the shops, offices (even public ones) are closed. Some people take holidays until after Tihar, which is celebrated about 2 weeks after Dashain. It is said that 70% of the population in Kathmandu leaves during this Dashain week. True enough, Kathmandu was virtually a ghost town. Gone was the usual beeping and honking of the cars, and people yelling to sell their merchandise. Instead, there was quiet, and clean air.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Basically we stayed at home enjoying the unusual eeriness of the city, but that doesn’t mean that we didn’t get to join in some of the festivities. 
These are a bunch of things we did that is pretty representative of how Dashain is celebrated. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;home-visits-cards-beer&quot;&gt;Home visits, cards, beer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We visited our family in Chapagaun for a fun gathering of relatives. Dashain is the time where people visit one another’s homes, and spend time with family. Though the majority of the people in Kathmandu had to travel far back home to their villages, because the Chapagaun family had relatives within the valley, they did not need to go out. The Chapagaun family was my host family when I first visited Nepal in 2013. Since then, they have always included me in their activities, and have taken care of me. We made some snacks, and spent the whole evening drinking, chatting and playing cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/dashain1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:600px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Take munching as usual…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/dashain2.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:600px;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
For the people who have to go out into the villages, many had to travel for one or two days, in overcrowded busses through dangerous roads. Accidents happened where the busses fall off from the narrow, rocky roads down the cliff. Apparently, some families split up the group into two busses, to avoid one whole family going down just in case. My friend said that she and her family walks 4 ~ 5 hours on the last stretch of the trip, for fear of getting into these kinds of accident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tika&quot;&gt;Tika&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The placing of the red Tika on the forehead performed by elders is another important ritual. The elders bless the younger ones with the Tika, hand them some money, and present a sacred yellow grass called “Jamara” to be placed behind the ear. While we were walking on the road on the 4th or 5th day of Dashain, we met the couple whom we usually bought eggs and milk from. Upon greeting them, we were promptly swept into their home. We were made to sit down, and surrounded by the amused group of relatives, the grandmother gave us the blessings. Then the feast was brought in, one item after another. We were fed thoroughly with various meat items (chicken, buffalo, wild goat, mutton) , eggs, milk tea, and pickles. I was touched by how welcoming the whole family was, generously offering us food, and their blessing. Especially when we barely could communicate with one another!  We were two random Japanese strangers, and they did not think twice about inviting us into their home to join in their religious rituals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/dashain3.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:330px; width:450px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;animal-sacrifices&quot;&gt;Animal sacrifices&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thousands of animals are sacrificed to the gods each year. Especially goats, that are looked on as a prized animal. We saw many goats being tied up to the front of the houses. Unfortunately, we witnessed some beheaded animals, and those that were being cleaned, just because they were quite openly performed. Apparently, there are some movements to stop this sacrificing of animals as an offering to God. At least the goats are eaten though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/dashain4.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:300px; height:400px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;My big Tika&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next up at the end of the month is Tihar! There will be another couple of days of holidays for this celebrated occasion. It’s pretty exciting to be in a country with so many festivities!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/10/22/Dashain.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/10/22/Dashain.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Achieving product/market fit</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In my previous blog &lt;a href=&quot;https://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/09/28/Lets-talk-about-failure.html&quot;&gt; “Let’s talk about startup failure and how to deal with it”&lt;/a&gt;, I talked a little bit about how we pivoted to releasing a completely remote course, without really elaborating on it or following up with the results. I’d like to look at our pivot here in context of product/market fit, being recently inspired by this concept from a blog post I read. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So rewinding back to what caused our pivot, basically we realised we had to change something to get out of the virtually zero paying customer state. We decided to offer a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.techrise.me/posts/techrise-core-immersive-and-techrise-core-remote-what-s-the-difference&quot;&gt; Remote package&lt;/a&gt;, a completely online program priced at 3,000 NPR (approx 30 USD). The price drop was huge compared to the original program priced a 12,000 NPR (approx 120 USD) - though the program was one month, unlike the two months previously offered. Mentor sessions were going to be carried out too, via Skype. I thought that this was an excellent package -  the program itself was almost nothing short of what was being offered in the original Immersive program. We could reach out to people who were living outside the valley, and people who were just a wee bit interested could learn without having to invest so much in it. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The response we observed were totally unexpected though&lt;/strong&gt;. As soon as we released the Remote package, there seemed to be more people interested in taking the 12,000 NPR Immersive course. We thought that people would be rushing to enroll in the Remote program, considering how affordable it was. It seemed like putting these programs side by side had the &lt;strong&gt;opposite effect&lt;/strong&gt;. Creating a contrast, instead seemed to have raised the expectations for the more Immersive program, and people began to perceive it as something of higher value. I thought that it was a matter of time, when graduates start earning from coding, people would see the true value in our two months course. It didn’t occur to us that a move like this would create a psychological dynamic that made people perceive the value of the programs in a different way. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately what we are trying to achieve here I think is &lt;em&gt;product/market fit&lt;/em&gt;. I recently read a blog post called &lt;a href=&quot; http://web.archive.org/web/20070701074943/http://blog.pmarca.com/2007/06/the-pmarca-gu-2.html&quot;&gt;“The Pmarca Guide to Startups, part 4: The only thing that matters”&lt;/a&gt;, which talks about product/market fit in a way that absolutely resognmated with me.  The article asserts that the most important thing for a startup was product/market fit, and that it was virtually what defined a successful startup. Conversely, startups that fail is because product/market fit never happened. Things like a great team, or great product was secondary, because ultimately whether your product would be consumed or not, was dependent on whether the &lt;em&gt;product matched the market perfectly&lt;/em&gt;. If the market was right, the offering could be subpar, and still people would want it. The article  stresses that it is necessary for startups to do everything necessary to get to that place including &lt;em&gt;“changing out people, rewriting your product, moving into a different market, telling customers no when you don’t want to, telling customers yes when you don’t want to, raising that fourth round of highly dilutive venture capital – whatever is required”&lt;/em&gt;. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The product that we have is the same, whether it be the Remote or Immersive Course. But by offering different price points, adapting the product to serve the market better, I think we are hoping to achieve is this product/market fit. We know that there is a market out there, but whether it be through targeting a different niche, or refining our product to speak to specific markets, we have to find a place where we can see the chemistry. The rise of interest in the Immersive Program was definitely an interesting outcome. I suppose this is part of the surprises along the way in experimenting, and trying to achieve product/market fit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/10/16/product:market-fit.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/10/16/product:market-fit.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What are your work productivity hacks?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One thing about my self, I’m a person that gets distracted pretty easily. I’m not good at focusing on one task at the same time for hours on end, like my partner Take. His focus is truly amazing – he would be on his computer the whole day coding if you let him. Sometimes I get jealous. I wish I had the ability to be as still as he is, without my mind and body wanting to roam around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Since i’m so scattered (please don’t see my room), I try to think of ways to keep myself preoccupied and productive, especially during our office time when I have to sit in the office from one to five - which is not a long time I know!. Kind of like productivity hacks, but not really I suppose, because they aren’t nearly as cool or unique enough to be &lt;i&gt;“hacks”&lt;/i&gt; . I’m definitely open to suggestions! &lt;br /&gt;
Here are some ways in which I try to keep myself moving and focused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;1.	Switching between tasks that uses different parts of the brain&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t know how the brain works, so scratch that, but I do try to do tasks that are different in nature, and that puts me in a different mood. For example; switching through blogging (which requires some creative thinking) and updating social media (which is relatively a no brainer), or going between learning some skills like coding, and reading up about industry related topics. Realizing my short-term concentration capacity, I try to get as much possible done by keeping my self alert with different material.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;2.	Coffee! &lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish. My mom brought the coffee machine from Japan, but even if we use it with the voltage converter, the breaker drops. Every time we try to use the coffee machine, especially during low shedding, we have to deal with the blaring beeping sound that tells us that there’s no electricity. Plus, the coffee we bought was stale or something. Oh, and we use a cloth as a filter because I couldn’t find them in the stores that I shop at. Definitely not very pretty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/coffee.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:300px; height:400px;&quot; /&gt;
Sadly we have surrendered back to instant Nescafe. At least it does the job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;3.	Making lists&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing I try to do is to make a list of things that needs to be done. This might be normal practice, but I find the productivity level to be so different when you actually visualize what’s necessary. I sometime use &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.techrise.me/posts/never-lose-track-of-your-tasks-again-project-management-like-a-pro-with-trello&quot;&gt;Trello&lt;/a&gt; because it lets my team members know what I’m working on, and allows me to move the task cards around based on the progress. But if it’s a menial task, I usually just make a quick memo of what I have to do today on a scratch paper. It definitely helps you from straying off track. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know they really aren’t cool &lt;i&gt;hacky stuff.&lt;/i&gt; But these are some things that i’ve been doing since I was young, and they have definitely helped me out a ton (especially 3).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are there any productivity hacks that you use during work? I would love to hear some creative new ways that helps you stay pumped!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/10/04/Productivity-Hacks.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/10/04/Productivity-Hacks.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Let’s talk about failure and how to deal with it</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Let’s talk about failure. &lt;strong&gt;Failure is a good thing in the startup world.&lt;/strong&gt; There’s almost a glorified connotation to the word “&lt;em&gt;failure”&lt;/em&gt; in startups. Fail fast and fail early, they say. 
So, given that failing is part of the process, are we actually ready to open up our arms to embrace it? &lt;br /&gt;
The truth is, probably not. Especially when it’s your first time.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Because the thing is, just because failure is bound to happen and it’s supposed to be absolutely normal, that doesn’t make it any less scary. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
It’s actually pretty terrifying. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/fail.gif&quot; style=&quot;height:330px; width:450px;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
So let me tell you a bit about our first encounter with failure. 
&lt;br /&gt;Basically, first month into our official launch of our business, we had near &lt;strong&gt;zero paying students&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
Getting the first paying customer is hard for any business.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;It was no exception for us.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Ever since we released our pricing page at 2 months for 15,000 NPR (approx 150 USD) around mid august, we were acquiring zero actual students. Even after reducing the price to a promotional 12,000NPR (approx 120 USD), the prospects didn’t look very promising. Sure we were capturing lots of attention; people seemed to like us on facebook, people were signing up, but &lt;em&gt;that didn’t mean that people were ready to hand over cash.&lt;/em&gt;
About 3 weeks after we launched the pricing page, we begin to sense that &lt;em&gt;something was wrong&lt;/em&gt;. We mulled around for a couple of days - every day we sort of bounced around the fact that we weren’t getting students but not really acknowledging the problem. I think we all had this bleak hope that maybe it was a matter of time before people would start appearing at our door, or maybe we just weren’t giving it much attention because our current (non-paying students) were doing so well.&lt;br /&gt;
But one day, it was blurted out. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;i&gt;Perhaps it was priced too high&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
 Now it was out there in the open, it was almost too obvious - &lt;strong&gt;the tuition was too expensive&lt;/strong&gt;. It wasn’t that there weren’t any other tutoring institutions priced similarly, but really, who was going to trust us with such an amount (considering that the average monthly disposable income was 21,444 NPR (approx 200 USD)?) People barely knew us, and we weren’t yet at the point where we could prove that learning with us was a worthwhile investment. &lt;strong&gt;We were trying to compete head to head with the top tier training institutes.&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There, we &lt;strong&gt;named our problem&lt;/strong&gt;. Now that we acknowledged our failure, we had to somehow make it right  - we had to take our first step to growth. &lt;br /&gt;
We had to find a &lt;strong&gt;viable solution to our problem&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
So we sat down together for the longest brainstorming / meeting session till date, and finally came up with what seemed like feasible plan that was worth testing out. &lt;br /&gt;
Basically we decided to throw out a completely different model with a different cost structure. We set out to &lt;strong&gt;differentiate ourselves from the conventional training institutes by putting our curriculum complete online&lt;/strong&gt; (our original course was a hybrid version of online learning and physical mentor sessions), and &lt;strong&gt;drastically lowering the price&lt;/strong&gt; (making the investment more low risk). &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/fail2.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:450px; width:450px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;True, we had no idea if this was going to succeed or if we were going to find ourselves in another dead end. But based on what we observed, this seemed like something that may work. 
&lt;br /&gt;
Earlier I said that failure, though anticipated, can be pretty scary especially if you let yourself. &lt;br /&gt;
I thought that if list out here some possible definitions of fear associate to failure, and how to combat it, things would be easier to handle in the future.&lt;br /&gt;
So what’s scary about failure again? &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;1. Uncertainty towards the decision about to be made&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no knowing if the decision will produce desired outcomes. What if we are focusing on a completely wrong issue and taking a completely wrong approach to things? So many “what ifs” are possible, and there’s no knowing if your next projection will lead to the right thing. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;2. Uncertainty towards the ability to  deliver upon the decision&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once we make the decision, it’s another entirely different matter whether we can actually live up to what we set out to do. There is always going to be some sort of anxiety around our ability to deliver, because if we don’t make it right this time, chances are that it would damage the business even further. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;3. The drop of motivation among the team&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Demotivation among the team is a possible side effect of failure of the business or project. People may be discouraged, and may lose that drive to push forward, which is fatal especially at the early stages of the organization. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, now that was pretty negative. But the real question here is, &lt;strong&gt;how can we combat these types of fears associated with failure?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
One important point I think is to &lt;strong&gt;involve everyone in the discussion process when making critical decisions for the company.&lt;/strong&gt; Obviously, this is going to be difficult when the company becomes larger, but by letting people take a stand in the decision making, employees would probably be more likely to take greater responsibility over their tasks, and actually try to make things work. Another is to &lt;strong&gt;focus the team on the positive aspects.&lt;/strong&gt; Celebrate small wins, and make sure there are positive outcomes that can keep the team’s spirit up. Making sure that there is tangible progress that can be celebrated however, I think requires deliberate engineering by the leader. Another is just to &lt;strong&gt;be confident.&lt;/strong&gt; If you are a leader in the position of making decisions, sometimes you just have to have faith in your choices - or at least show that you do. Sometimes the best way to override everyone’s uncertainty is to &lt;em&gt;pretend that you know what you are doing&lt;/em&gt;. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point of failure in startups I think, is to make sure that you can &lt;strong&gt;learn from your mistakes as quickly as possible.&lt;/strong&gt; So in the future you can sniff out any similar pitfalls, or if you do fall into another failure trap, you and your team can be &lt;strong&gt;more responsive towards it&lt;/strong&gt;. Keep learning, and I think it will gradually become easier for the team to pick themselves up in any kind of situations. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we go beyond our fears, i’m sure we will be able to embrace failure in a way that will allow us to grow. Turning failure into positive energy definitely needs some will power and practice, but I believe that it is key to the success of any kind of startup or organization.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/09/28/Lets-talk-about-failure.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/09/28/Lets-talk-about-failure.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Natsuko&#39;s mom in Nepal Part 2!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My mom left last monday after her 10 day trip in Nepal. 
I’m so glad she was able to finally come to the country that i’ve been talking about non stop for 4 years now, and meet all the people who have been by my side since my first visit here. 
I was once again truly amazed and touched by everyone’s hospitality towards a complete foreigner who was just here for a short trip. My friends enthusiastically explained to her their history and culture, and made it a point to be part of her experience here in Nepal. I was comfortable enough to send her to Emerald English School in Chapagaun and to the massage therapist at edge of the city, because I knew there were reliable people waiting for her on the other end. Sure enough, my mom came back both times happy with new friends and new knowledge about Nepal.
&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;
One of the most memorable part of the second half of her trip was the hike at Telkot. 
We went for a day hiking trip with the TECHRISE gang to Telkot, which is located about 30 minutes away from Bhaktapur by bus. It was raining that morning, but we all met up at the Bhaktapur bus stop at 8:00 am. We ended up leisurely drinking tea, strolling around the famous water ponds, looking for something to eat because we realised that we needed food before going up, and then settling down to eat. When we finally made our way to Telkot, it was almost 11:00 pm. This doesn’t bother me one bit though, because &lt;i&gt;that’s how we roll in Nepal.&lt;/i&gt;
&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/telkot3.JPG&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:600px;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/telkot9.JPG&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:600px;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Once we were on higher grounds we found a tree that bore Lapsi, a fruit that apparently is only found in Nepal. It was usually eaten in a dried and seasoned form, as a pickle or candy. We picked some off the ground, and threw our shoes at the tree to shake more off. The fruit was still unripe, but the unique fleshiness and sourness of it was pleasing to suck on. 
&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/telkot1.JPG&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:600px;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/telkot2.JPG&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:600px;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We went through the mountains for about 4 or 5 hours observing the different foliage and the occasional goats or dogs. The air was fresh and clean, unlike the dusty polluted roads down in the city. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/telkot5.JPG&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:600px;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/telkot7.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:700px; height:200px;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The hike ended at Changu Narayan, the oldest temple in Nepal. The oldest inscription on the stone pillar was dated back to 464 AD. These aged carvings had been through countless changes in society, and fluctuations in climate - no wonder there was an ancient majestic feel to the place that could not be ignored. It’s astonishing how people in the ancient times were so advanced in their skills, and dedicated to creating so many of these temples and monuments.
I was extremely tired from all the walking which I wasn’t used to, but it was definitely a change of scenery for our daily lives.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/telkot6.JPG&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:600px;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/telkot8.JPG&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:600px;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
On my mom’s last day Neekesh, Sabina, and the rest of the gang threw her a surprise farewell party with a cake! I was touched, and so was my unexpecting mom too i’m sure. We enjoyed our last evening with laughter and home cooked Japanese food on the terrace.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/mom2-1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:600px; height:440px; &quot; /&gt;
&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;
To some, a trip to Nepal may be just a fleeting moment, a mere destination out of the many possible expedition around the world. But somehow I see many people being drawn back here. I think it’s something about the people, something about the majestic temples and buildings among the overly crowded dusty roads that calls people back to Kathmandu.
I hope that my mom also feels the same - that someday she would want to come back again, to walk the streets by the temples, to have the sugary cups masala tea, and to greet those who welcomed her with open arms. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/mom2-2.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:600px;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Mom looking sad at the airport.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Bye mom, see you again soon!&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/09/27/Mom-in-Nepal2.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/09/27/Mom-in-Nepal2.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Natsuko&#39;s mom in Nepal!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Natsuko’s mom in Nepal!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My daily schedule has been definitely different these days. That’s because my mom – Monica Shinozaki is here for the first time in Nepal!
I have been bugging her to come to Nepal and she’s finally decided to come all the way from Japan!
So I’ve been pretty busy bringing her hear and there, revisiting the tourists sights I went to 4 years ago when I first came. I realized that ever since Take and I have arrived, 2months ago we have literally not done any form of sight seeing. It’s been great refreshment, seeing Nepal with a new pair of eyes and eating some good food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To give a quick overview of the past couple of days…&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Day 1&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
In the morning we went to the almighty tourist location in Kathmandu – Thamel! I generally avoid the Kathmandu side (we are located in Lalitpur, a district right next to Kathmandu) because it feels much dustier and somewhat unfamiliar, but I took a step outside of my comfort zone to bring her around the city. 
Change 1 (from my daily life): Get out of Lalitpur (out of our house for that matter). 
Followed immediately by, 
Change 2: Travel by Taxi. 
I’m usually willing to pay 15 ~30 Nepalese Rupees (approx. 15 ~30 cents) for my transportation on a public vehicle. 300 NPR for the same distance? Pfffttt. PLEASE. The ride was a lot more comfortable though. A LOT MORE. 
Anyways, in Thamel we went around hunting for the shawls, the crafts, the jewelries, and all the other artisan products. Each shop has something special, and they really are not the same in every store. We found a store that had some really beautiful paper crafts like lampshades, ornaments and calendars. We even found a kettle coaster made out of small woolen balls. A random, solitary piece, but we impulsively decided to get it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/furry.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:330px; width:450px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the evening we went to the charity event for my host brother’s NGO (he was my host brother 4 years ago): Help to Needy Children. It was a live music event at a restaurant bar, and we had so much fun! We loved all the Nepali songs played by the local band. Everyone from young to old was dancing and having a blast with the hit numbers. I was able to put into good use the dance moves I learnt during Teej.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/party.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:600px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 2&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Take’s Birthday Breakfast at our favorite Café!
Change 3:  Having actual FOOD at the café - not just coffee. 
Poor expats that we are, we usually just order coffee. But this time we had some gorgeous breakfast food! Thank you mom! I’m not used to eating so much in the morning anymore, I was slightly giddy by the end of the meal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/soma1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:600px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the evening we went to see a Western and Nepali fusion Opera “Arjuna’s Dilenma”.  Produced by the One Young World Theaters, this kind of fusion opera was the first of its kind in Nepal. The production was at the courtyard of the Patan Museum, and it was beautiful with the temples looming in the background. The museum itself is an old majestic building with intricate carvings on the wood and decorated with sturdy looking bronze pieces. The Opera was amazing too – there was traditional music, Jazz, a women choir group, a sax player, a ballet dancer, and all sorts of other performing art forms to depict the scenes and emotions set around Krishna and Arjun. I was spell bound for the whole 70 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 3&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
It was raining the whole day today! So my mother decided to take initiative to do some volunteer work here. 
Change 4: Innovation in the Kitchen 
She took it upon herself to renovate the whole kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/mom.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:300px; height:400px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She pulled out all the 100 yen shop supplies that I brought here previously and totally reformed the place. She organized everything in different compartments, set up racks to hang up thing, put curtains to cover up the storage, and even placed some styrohfome lying around on the wall for a funky touch. I didn’t think my kitchen was so bad before but now looking at the transformation I was blown away. This was true innovation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the evening we went to Mangal Bazaar. We walked inside the square and did a whole big round going through the small alleyways. Mangal Bazaar is one of my favorite places, because people’s lives were so closely integrated with the ancient buildings and temples. People simply sat around them watching the world go by, or would buy some things at the small stores that dominated the street side. It’s not the case where the temples are strictly restricted to it being a tourist spot, and people’s daily lives being something else. They co-existed, and I loved that atmosphere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/mangal.JPG&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:600px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The nice thing about shopping at these local stores in Nepal is that people don’t really try to rip tourists off. There are comparatively less people who demand for a exorbitant price, and they don’t really push you into buying things. I can hold a friendly conversation, learn about them and the products before deciding to make a purchase. And that generally works, because we feel more inclined to by it then simply walking away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The adventures to be continued!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/09/15/Mom-in-Nepal.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/09/15/Mom-in-Nepal.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Teej - Fasting for the First Time!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I got to experience my first &lt;strong&gt;Teej&lt;/strong&gt;, the largest women’s festival in Nepal! Teej is a celebration where women gather together to fast for the longevity and health of their husbands, worship at the temples and dance. My Nepali sister Depa first told me about this festival four years ago, and she was super excited when she knew that I would be here during this time. In fact, that was one of the first things she exclaimed about - that I would finally be able to celebrate Teej with her - when I said that I would be staying in Nepal for the whole year. &lt;strong&gt;This was something I could not miss&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all started with my dress picking for the day, about a week ago. Two of my friends brought me out to shop for the perfect garment for the occasion. In the small Sari shop that I was brought to in Mangal Bazar (I honestly don’t know how people find these stores in the nook and crooks of the street), I was thrown a whole array of options. &lt;i&gt;Choosing these garments are an intense matter&lt;/i&gt;. I tried them on, one after another. After much prodding, twirling, and tightening of the loose cloth on my body, we settled on a blue and orange Lehenga. After that we also went to pick out the shoes, accessories, and fixed the Lehenga at the tailor shop -  all with deliberate contemplation. Then finally I was set for the day.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Teej this year fell on Sunday. So from Saturday evening, I went over to Depa’s house and enjoyed a feast of all kinds of delicious dishes and sweets. All Depa’s relatives from young to old, we  all pre-danced in our pyjamas. We went pretty wild, thrusting out our moves to the music from the cell phone. We ate again at 11 pm, just before it turned the next day when we had to begin our fast. I was not very hungry but I helped myself to the late night feast of coconut and almond mixed rice, yogurt, and some traditional sweets. I was full to the max but still ate because I was pretty nervous about feeling hungry the next day.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/teej6.JPG&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:600px;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up not hungry, but still I was a bit worried about how I could go through the day without drinking any water or food till sunset. But the purpose of the festival wasn’t endurance, so I tried to brush the thought out of my head and enjoy the day. We got up and began preparing for our visit to the temple, which basically meant putting on lots of make up. I’ve never put on so much makeup, but it felt pretty great having myself- beautified and being told that I look like a Nepali girl (um, girl?!). The temple was a vibrant color of red and green with the beautifully embroided Saris. Look at these beauties! &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/teej5.JPG&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:600px;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/teej1.JPG&quot; style=&quot;height:330px; width:450px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/teej2.JPG&quot; style=&quot;height:330px; width:450px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/teej3.JPG&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:600px;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok I’m going to spill the beans but I was not able to do a full fasting that day. After becoming all hot and sweaty from dancing, I gave into drinking water. I swear I could have endured it but when some of my friends drank some water, I just couldn’t resist. I abstained from eating food till sunset though. I never imagined that it was be so hard, I felt pretty dizzy and low on energy by 3pm. Again it’s probably because I wasn’t entirely fasting for a purpose, I was fasting more for formality. Depa always used to tell me that the days she fasts she never feels hungry, but instead feels good from the purity of what she is doing and the holiness associated with it. It was an interesting experience to fast, putting myself in the shoes of so many others who fast as part of their religion. The act definitely takes a toll on the body. But the beliefs associated now I see now is &lt;i&gt;so powerful and meaningful&lt;/i&gt; to those who practice it, that it is far more gratifying than satisfying the immediate needs of your body. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I had my first bite of the milky sweets at 5pm, I felt the sugar in it flowing through my blood and nourishing my body. &lt;i&gt;I felt revitalized&lt;/i&gt;. I was amazed at how that little piece could give me so much energy.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/teej7.JPG&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:600px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I came back for the night, but I will be returning back again tomorrow for another full day of dancing in the temple. I’m super grateful to Depa and her family for inviting me to be part of their family festivities, and Nepali culture. I loved all the colors and the joy in the air, and i’m definitely looking forward tomorrow for another day of dancing and fun (and this time food!). 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/teej8.JPG&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:600px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/09/05/Teej.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/09/05/Teej.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Our First 30 Day Sprint</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been &lt;i&gt;a month&lt;/i&gt; since we officially launched TECHRISE in Nepal. The days have flown by super quickly but it has certainly been a fruitful couple of weeks. To mark this first month, I’d like to reflect over our accomplishments (keeping things positive here!) and some things we would be focusing on going forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To sum up our first month, more than reaching our goals as a company, I think our success would be defined in terms of the of initial &lt;strong&gt;&lt;i&gt;“company culture”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; we created. Although I think that company culture is super important, it’s not so easy when there are geography based cultures that we have to consider first. Trying to understand the ways and values that we each grew up with, is vital in making things work in all spectrums of the business. &lt;i&gt;Company culture&lt;/i&gt; is what will be ultimately handed down, and is what I believe will help propel us forward through the various changes we would go through over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of these &lt;i&gt;cultural&lt;/i&gt; things that we cultivated I think is the &lt;strong&gt;experiment and go&lt;/strong&gt; mentality. We tested and changed so many things over the past 30 days -  from the wording of the “call to action” button on the landing page, to our strategies on how we approach potential students. We could list a bunch of things that we implemented, and they would all be things that we never thought would exist a month ago. Like I said before in my blog posts on &lt;a href=&quot;https://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/08/24/Stand-Up-Meetings.html&quot;&gt;stand up meetings&lt;/a&gt;, the constant loop of experimentation  and iteration I think is what helps us determine what is working and what doesn’t. Everyone on the team shoots out ideas, and we try them out as &lt;strong&gt;quickly&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;cost effectively&lt;/strong&gt; as possible. For example if we run facebook ads, we would test it out with a small budget first before launching a longer campaign, or if we want to hold events, we would first present to our current students and get feedback before going public (we did 4 events this month - &lt;a href=&quot;https://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/08/26/Freelancing-Event-Round-2.html&quot;&gt;“How to Start Your Freelancing Career”&lt;/a&gt; and a “Blogging with Jekyll” workshop).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another positive I think is that we’re beginning to realise the &lt;strong&gt;communal aspect&lt;/strong&gt; as one of the intergrel values of TECHRISE. The intimacy between the students and the mentors, as well as between the students themselves, is really what fosters a group identity that keeps them motivated. It also helps that they are a pretty high quality and driven bunch to begin with, since they were pre-screened through some assignments before being admitted. Hands down to Take and Aadesh for the great mentor-student relationship, they have been answering students questions on slack and facebook almost 24/7. And trust me they get &lt;i&gt;a lot of questions&lt;/i&gt;. The students regard themselves as part of the TECHRISE family, and it’s great because they actively help one another out, and they are the walking proof that TECHRISE is a working model. This small tight-knit community will not be the same as we expand, but I think part of the challenge in the future is how we can maintain this closeness with a much larger and diverse group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going forward, there are a couple of things that we want to focus, especially in the upcoming month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Educating ourselves on our respective roles&lt;/strong&gt; – We have our respective roles: Take and Aadesh are mentors and platform developers, while Lakshman and I take on more of the business and marketing side of TECHRISE. In the past week we purchased some resources - &lt;i&gt;Upcase&lt;/i&gt; for further learning Ruby on Rails, and &lt;i&gt;Code School&lt;/i&gt; for some web design stuff (they were doing a great promotion). We also dug up some online free certification courses like &lt;i&gt;Hubspot&lt;/i&gt; marketing courses. Other than our day to day operations, we will be taking some time boosting our skills up so that we can really excel at what we do.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Understanding our potential students and making more data driven decisions&lt;/strong&gt; – We are now getting a better picture of who are attracted to the things we do at TECHRISE, and who our mission speaks to most.  Identifying the specific needs of our potential clients and illustrating them as &lt;i&gt;audience personas&lt;/i&gt; would help us deliver contents that are on point. We are currently no master at analyzing data, but we really need to start deeply examining our analytics to determine our next moves.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reaching out directly to students&lt;/strong&gt; - Along with understanding our customer base, we also want to start directly approaching students. Up till now we have relied mostly on facebook marketing and some interaction with students through our workshop events. Going to schools and meetups would give us a chance to find out more about who they are and what they want. We think that there are many more people out there that would benefit from TECHRISE, but they just aren’t familiar with the bootcamps concept or about Ruby on Rails.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This frst month really was a sprint, but September probably would be no different. It will be a long time more before we can enter the jogging phase. We’re all enjoying ourselves though, and waking up each day cannot be more exciting ;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/09/05/First-month.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/09/05/First-month.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Gap Between the Job Market and Higher Education in the IT Field</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After stuffing ourselves, we returned back to the office to host our small discussion session event at TECHRISE. We invited a couple of startup guys, web developers and some college administrators. The purpose of the session was to discuss about the existing gap between the &lt;strong&gt;job market and higher education in the IT field&lt;/strong&gt;. I wanted to bring to one table these people who all worked in this field but in various spaces, to have a frank and open discussion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/discussion1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:590px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through our nearly two-hour conversation we realized that the gap that we were trying to identify was not only limited to simply the gap between what is required by the job market and what is being taught at the educational institutions. There were multiple so-called &lt;i&gt;gaps&lt;/i&gt;, which all came into play to create this disparity and disconnect. Some of these gaps that we identified were:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The gap between the &lt;i&gt;demands from the &lt;strong&gt;industry&lt;/strong&gt; (wants experienced and qualified individuals) and the &lt;strong&gt;students&lt;/strong&gt; (do not have any experience and very little qualifications)&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The gap between the &lt;i&gt;skills students acquire and what is required from the job market&lt;/i&gt; – Many of the concepts and content are outdated and not in demand&lt;/li&gt;


&lt;li&gt;The gap between the &lt;i&gt;talent the students wish to supply and the demand from the market&lt;/i&gt; - There are not enough industries that are monetizable. People cannot make a living unless you are working in a highly in demand sector (not limited to the IT sector)&lt;/li&gt; &lt;br /&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/discussion2.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:440px; width:590px;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other interesting points that came up were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The lack of motivation among students – perhaps linked to the fact that there are limited opportunities to see how what they learned can be applied to the real world&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The importance of students nurturing a problem solving attitude, instead of a passive learning one&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The culture of &lt;i&gt;blame&lt;/i&gt;: students blaming teachers for not being able to understand and perform, and vice versa teachers blaming students&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were so many factors that were interrelated to constructing this discrepancy. The conversation is a never-ending one with no real conclusion. But from the discussion, I think we came to realize that there are two roles that we can take on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.	To inspire the students to apply their skills to the real world, and motivate them to pursue further with academics at school &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.	Help them become real problem solvers through curriculum design (you can learn more about the TECHRISE learning system though this  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.techrise.me/posts/how-techrise-creates-superstar-coders&quot;&gt;  blog &lt;/a&gt;) and providing more opportunities to work on real live projects &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an educational entity that really cares about doing what’s best for the students and their learning, we found everyone’s insights extremely valuable. Their willingness to sacrifice a Saturday afternoon to hold this conversation really showed their passion towards what they did in this field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a long day for us but a really meaningful weekend!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
        <link>http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/08/28/Discussion-Event.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://naztshinozaki.github.io/2016/08/28/Discussion-Event.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
